Guide to the Rights and Wrongs Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Stock Footage, Circa 1990-1996; Series II
  - RT93 3235, 1993 February 26 (Box 88)
  - RT93 3236, 1993 May 21 (Box 88)
  - RT93 3237, 1993 March 1 (Box 88)
  - RT93 3238, 1991 December 5 (Box 88)
  - RT93 3239, 1990 March 1 (Box 88)
  - RT93 3241, Undated (Box 88)
  - RT93 3242, 1993 May 15 (Box 88)
  - RT93 3247, 1993 June 7 (Box 88)
  - RT93 3248, 1993 June 7 (Box 88)
  - RT93 3249, Undated (Box 88)
  - RT93 3250, Undated (Box 88)
  - RT93 3251, 1993 June 4 (Box 89)
  - RT93 3253, Undated (Box 89)
  - RT93 3254, Undated (Box 89)
  - RT93 3255, 1993 June 7 (Box 89)
  - RT93 3257, Undated (Box 89)
  - RT93 3258, Undated (Box 89)
  - RT93 3259, 1993 June 1 (Box 89)
  - RT93 3260, Undated (Box 89)
  - RT93 3261, Undated (Box 89)
  - RT93 3262, Undated (Box 89)
  - RT93 3263, Undated (Box 89)
  - RT93 3264, Undated (Box 89)
  - RT93 3265, Undated (Box 89)
  - RT93 3266, 1993 March 1 (Box 89)
  - RT93 3267, 1993 March 1 (Box 89)
  - RT93 3268, 1993 June 6 (Box 89)
  - RT93 3271, 1993 June 1 (Box 90)
  - RT93 3272, 1993 June 1 (Box 90)
  - RT93 3273, Undated (Box 90)
  - RT93 3276, Undated (Box 90)
  - RT93 3277, Undated (Box 90)
  - RT93 3278, 1993 June 24 (Box 90)
  - RT93 3279, 1993 June 16 (Box 90)
  - RT93 3280, 1993 June 1 (Box 90)
  - RT93 3281, 1993 March 12 (Box 90)
  - RT93 3282, 1993 June 1 (Box 90)
  - RT93 3283, 1993 May 1 (Box 90)
  - RT93 3284, 1993 May 1 (Box 90)
  - RT93 3287, Undated (Box 90)
  - RT93 3288, Undated (Box 90)
  - RT93 3289, 1993 March 1 (Box 90)
  - RT93 3290, 1992 June 18 (Box 90)
  - RT93 3291, Undated (Box 90)
  - RT93 3292, 1993 March 15 (Box 90)
  - RT93 3293, Undated (Box 91)
  - RT93 3294, Undated (Box 91)
  - RT93 3295, Undated (Box 91)
  - RT93 3296, 1993 April 25 (Box 91)
  - RT93 3297, 1993 April 25 (Box 91)
  - RT93 3298, 1993 April 25 (Box 91)
  - RT93 3302, 1993 June 1 (Box 91)
  - RT93 3303, Undated (Box 91)
  - RT93 3304, 1993 June 1 (Box 91)
  - RT93 3307, Undated (Box 91)
  - RT93 3314, 1993 March 22 (Box 91)
  - RT93 3317, Undated (Box 91)
  - RT93 3318, Undated (Box 91)
  - RT93 3319, Undated (Box 91)
  - RT93 3320, Undated (Box 91)
  - RT93 3321, 1993 July 1 (Box 91)
  - RT93 3322, Undated (Box 91)
  - RT93 3323, 1993 July 6 (Box 91)
  - RT93 3324, Undated (Box 91)
  - RT93 3325, Undated (Box 92)
  - RT93 3326, Undated (Box 92)
  - RT93 3327, Undated (Box 92)
  - RT93 3328, Undated (Box 92)
  - RT93 3329, Undated (Box 92)
  - RT93 3333, Undated (Box 92)
  - RT93 3334, Undated (Box 92)
  - RT93 3335, Undated (Box 92)
  - RT 3000, 1988 March 18 (Box 93)
  - RT 3301, 1995 March 13 (Box 93)
  - RT 3001, 1995 March 13 (Box 93)
  - RT 3002, Undated (Box 93)
  - RT 3002, Undated (Box 93)
  - RT 3003, Undated (Box 93)
  - RT 3004, Undated (Box 93)
  - RT 3004, Undated (Box 93)
  - RT 3005, Undated (Box 93)
  - RT 3006, 1995 March 13 (Box 93)
  - RT 3009, Undated (Box 93)
  - RT 3010, Undated (Box 93)
  - RT 3011, Undated (Box 93)
  - RT 3012, Undated (Box 93)
  - RT 3013, 1996 May 1 (Box 93)
  - RT 3014, 1996 May 5 (Box 93)
  - RT 3015, 1996 May 7 (Box 93)
  - RT 3016, Undated (Box 93)
  - RT 3017, 1996 April 15 (Box 93)
  - RT 3018, Undated (Box 93)
  - RT 3019, Undated (Box 93)
  - RT 3020, Undated (Box 93)
  - RT 3021, Undated (Box 93)
  - RT 3022, 1995 January 15 (Box 93)
  - RT 3023, 1995 May 7 (Box 94)
  - RT 3024, Undated (Box 94)
  - RT 3025, 1996 May 14 (Box 94)
  - RT 3027, 1995 June 15 (Box 94)
  - RT 3028, 1994 September 20 (Box 94)
  - RT 3029, 1995 November 29 (Box 94)
  - RT 3030, 1995 October 31 (Box 94)
  - RT 3031, Undated (Box 94)
  - RT 3032, 1994 December 15 (Box 94)
  - RT 3033, 1994 December 15 (Box 94)
  - RT 3034, Undated (Box 94)
  - RT 3035, Undated (Box 94)
  - RT 3036, Undated (Box 94)
  - RT 3037, Undated (Box 94)
  - RT 3038, Undated (Box 94)
  - RT 3039, Undated (Box 94)
  - RT 3040, 1993 January 24 (Box 94)
  - RT 3041, Undated (Box 94)
  - RT 3042, Undated (Box 94)
  - RT 3043, Undated (Box 94)
  - RT 3044, 1989 November 21 (Box 94)
  - RT 3045, 1994 May 26 (Box 94)
  - RT 3046, 1996 January 1 (Box 95)
  - RT 3047, Undated (Box 95)
  - RT 3048, Undated (Box 95)
  - RT 3049, 1996 March 26 (Box 95)
  - RT 3050, Undated (Box 95)
  - RT 3051, Undated (Box 95)
  - RT 3052, Undated (Box 95)
  - RT 3053, Undated (Box 95)
  - RT 3054, Undated (Box 95)
  - RT 3055, Undated (Box 95)
  - RT 3056, Undated (Box 95)
  - RT 3057, Undated (Box 95)
  - RT 3058, 1987 April 21 (Box 95)
  - RT 3059, 1996 May 14 (Box 95)
  - RT 3060, Undated (Box 95)
  - RT 3061, 1996 May 13 (Box 95)
  - RT 3062, Undated (Box 95)
  - RT 3063, Undated (Box 95)
  - RT 3064, Undated (Box 95)
  - RT 3065, Undated (Box 95)
  - RT 3065A, Undated (Box 95)
  - RT 3066, 1996 April 15 (Box 95)
  - RT 3067, Undated (Box 95)
  - RT96 3068, Undated (Box 96)
  - RT96 3071, Undated (Box 96)
  - RT96 3072, Undated (Box 96)
  - RT96 3074, 1993 November 15 (Box 96)
  - RT96 3075, Undated (Box 96)
  - RT96 3083, 1996 April 22 (Box 96)
  - RT96 3087, 1996 May 28 (Box 96)
  - RT96 3088, Undated (Box 96)
  - RT96 3089, 1996 May 13 (Box 96)
  - RT96 3090, Undated (Box 96)
  - RT96 3091, Undated (Box 96)
  - RT96 3093, 1996 May 17 (Box 96)
  - RT96 3095, 1996 May 1 (Box 96)
  - RT96 3096, Undated (Box 96)
  - RT96 3100, Undated (Box 96)
  - RT96 3101, Undated (Box 96)
  - RT96 3102, Undated (Box 96)
  - RT96 3103, 1996 May 28 (Box 97)
  - RT96 3104, 1996 May 28 (Box 97)
  - RT96 3105, 1996 April 8 (Box 97)
  - RT96 3106, Undated (Box 97)
  - RT96 3107, 1995 April 28 (Box 97)
  - RT96 3108, Undated (Box 97)
  - RT96 3109, 1993 November 16 (Box 97)
  - RT96 3110, 1989 July 5 (Box 97)
  - RT96 3112, 1996 March 15 (Box 97)
  - RT96 3113, 1996 March 15 (Box 97)
  - RT96 3114, Undated (Box 97)
  - RT96 3116, 1996 April 8 (Box 97)
  - RT96 3117, 1996 May 15 (Box 97)
  - RT96 3118, 1996 June 6 (Box 98)
  - RT96 3119, 1996 June 6 (Box 98)
  - RT96 3120, 1996 June 6 (Box 98)
  - RT96 3121, 1996 June 6 (Box 98)
  - RT96 3122, 1996 June 6 (Box 98)
  - RT96 3123, 1996 June 6 (Box 98)
  - RT96 3124, 1996 June 6 (Box 98)
  - RT96 3125, 1996 June 6 (Box 98)
  - RT96 3126, 1996 June 6 (Box 98)
  - RT96 3127, 1996 June 6 (Box 98)
  - RT96 3128, 1996 June 6 (Box 98)
  - RT96 3129, 1996 April 15 (Box 98)
  - RT96 3130, 1995 April 15 (Box 98)
  - RT96 3131, 1996 April 25 (Box 99)
  - RT96 3132, 1996 April 25 (Box 99)
  - RT96 3133, 1991 June 10 (Box 99)
  - RT96 3134, 1996 April 4 (Box 99)
  - RT96 3135, Undated (Box 99)
  - RT96 3136, Undated (Box 99)
  - RT96 3137, Undated (Box 99)
  - RT96 3138, Undated (Box 99)
  - RT96 3139, Undated (Box 99)
  - RT96 3140, Undated (Box 99)
  - RT96 3141, Undated (Box 99)
  - RT96 3142, Undated (Box 99)
  - RT96 3141, Undated (Box 99)
  - RT96 3144, Undated (Box 99)
  - RT96 3145, Undated (Box 99)
  - RT96 3146, Undated (Box 99)
  - RT96 3147, Undated (Box 99)
  - RT96 3148, Undated (Box 99)
  - RT96 3149, Undated (Box 99)
  - RT96 3151, Undated (Box 99)
  - RT96 3152, Undated (Box 99)
  - RT96 3153, Undated (Box 99)
  - RT96 3155, 1990 February 11 (Box 100)
  - RT96 3156, 1990 February 11 (Box 100)
  - RT96 3157, 1996 June 15 (Box 100)
  - RT96 3158, 1996 April 3 (Box 100)
  - RT96 3159, Undated (Box 100)
  - RT96 3160, 1996 May 30 (Box 100)
  - RT96 3161, 1996 June 17 (Box 100)
  - RT96 3161, 1996 June 17 (Box 100)
  - RT96 3162, Undated (Box 100)
  - RT96 3163, Undated (Box 100)
  - RT96 3164, 1996 February 15 (Box 100)
  - RT96 3165, 1990 September 15 (Box 100)
  - RT96 3166, 1990 September 15 (Box 100)
  - RT96 3167, 1994 September 15 (Box 100)
  - RT96 3168, Undated (Box 100)
  - RT96 3169, Undated (Box 100)
  - RT96 3170, Undated (Box 100)
  - RT96 3171, Undated (Box 100)
  - RT96 3172, Undated (Box 101)
  - RT96 3172, 1996 July 9 (Box 101)
  - RT96 3173, 1996 April 14 (Box 101)
  - RT96 3174, 1996 November 13 (Box 101)
  - RT96 3175, 1996 May 6 (Box 101)
  - RT96 3176, Undated (Box 101)
  - RT96 3171, Undated (Box 101)
  - RT96 3178, Undated (Box 101)
  - RT96 3179, Undated (Box 101)
  - RT96 3180, Undated (Box 101)
  - RT96 3181, 1996 July 15 (Box 101)
  - RT96 3182, 1996 July 10 (Box 101)
  - RT96 3183, Undated (Box 101)
  - RT96 3184, Undated (Box 101)
  - RT96 3185, 1996 June 28 (Box 101)
  - RT96 3186, 1996 June 28 (Box 101)
  - RT96 3187, 1996 May 23 (Box 101)
  - RT96 3188, Undated (Box 101)
  - RT96 3189, Undated (Box 101)
  - RT96 3190, Undated (Box 101)
  - RT96 3193, Undated (Box 101)
  - RT96 3194, Undated (Box 101)
  - RT96 3195, Undated (Box 101)
  - RT96 3196, Undated (Box 101)
  - RT96 3197, Undated (Box 101)
  - RT96 3198, Undated (Box 101)
  - RT96 3199, Undated (Box 101)
  - RT96 3200, Undated (Box 102)
  - RT96 3201, Undated (Box 102)
  - RT96 3102, Undated (Box 102)
  - RT96 3203, Undated (Box 102)
  - RT96 3204, 1996 July 11 (Box 102)
  - RT96 3205, Undated (Box 102)
  - RT96 3207, Undated (Box 102)
  - RT96 3208, Undated (Box 102)
  - RT96 3209, 1996 June 6 (Box 102)
  - RT96 3210, Undated (Box 102)
  - RT96 3211, Undated (Box 102)
  - RT96 3212, Undated (Box 102)
  - RT96 3213, Undated (Box 102)
  - RT96 3214, Undated (Box 102)
  - RT96 3215, Undated (Box 102)
  - RT96 3216, 1996 November 9 (Box 102)
  - RT96 3216, 1996 November 9 (Box 102)
  - RT96 3217, Undated (Box 102)
  - RT96 3217, Undated (Box 102)
  - RT96 3218, 1996 April 23 (Box 102)
  - RT96 3219, Undated (Box 102)
  - RT96 3220, Undated (Box 102)
  - RT96 3221, Undated (Box 102)
  - RT96 3222, Undated (Box 102)
  - RT96 3223, Undated (Box 103)
  - RT96 3224, Undated (Box 103)
  - RT96 3226, Undated (Box 103)
  - RT96 3227, Undated (Box 103)
  - RT96 3228, Undated (Box 103)
  - RT96 3229, Undated (Box 103)
  - RT96 3230, Undated (Box 103)
  - RT96 3231, Undated (Box 103)
  - RT96 3232, Undated (Box 103)
  - RT96 3233, 1996 June 21 (Box 103)
  - RT96 3234, Undated (Box 103)
  - RT96 3235, Undated (Box 103)
  - RT96 3236, Undated (Box 103)
  - RT96 3237, Undated (Box 103)
  - RT96 3238, 1995 July 25 (Box 103)
  - RT96 3239, Undated (Box 103)
  - RT96 3240, Undated (Box 103)
  - RT96 3241, Undated (Box 103)
  - RT96 3242, Undated (Box 103)
  - RT96 3243, 1995 August 22 (Box 103)
  - RT96 3244, 1996 September 15 (Box 103)
  - RT96 3245, 1996 September 15 (Box 103)
  - RT96 3246, Undated (Box 103)
  - RT96 3247, Undated (Box 103)
  - RT96 3248, Undated (Box 103)
  - RT96 3249, Undated (Box 104)
  - RT96 3250, Undated (Box 104)
  - RT96 3251, Undated (Box 104)
  - RT96 3252, 1996 June 10 (Box 104)
  - RT96 3253, Undated (Box 104)
  - RT96 3254, Undated (Box 104)
  - RT96 3255, Undated (Box 104)
  - RT96 3256, Undated (Box 104)
  - RT96 3257, Undated (Box 104)
  - RT96 3258, Undated (Box 104)
  - RT96 3259, Undated (Box 104)
  - RT96 3261, Undated (Box 104)
  - RT96 3262, Undated (Box 104)
  - RT96 3263, 1996 May 30 (Box 104)
  - RT96 3264, Undated (Box 104)
  - RT96 3265, Undated (Box 104)
  - RT96 3266, Undated (Box 104)
  - RT96 3266, Undated (Box 104)
  - RT96 3267, Undated (Box 104)
  - RT96 3268, Undated (Box 104)
  - RT96 3269, Undated (Box 104)
  - RT96 3270, 1996 January 15 (Box 104)
  - RT96 3271, Undated (Box 104)
  - RT96 3272, Undated (Box 105)
  - RT96 3273, Undated (Box 105)
  - RT96 3274, 1995 August 15 (Box 105)
  - RT96 3275, 1995 August 15 (Box 105)
  - RT96 3276, 1995 August 15 (Box 105)
  - RT96 3277, 1993 June 28 (Box 105)
  - RT96 3278, Undated (Box 105)
  - RT96 3279, Undated (Box 105)
  - RT96 3280, 1995 July 6 (Box 105)
  - RT96 3281, Undated (Box 105)
  - RT96 3282, Undated (Box 105)
  - RT96 3283, 1996 April 23 (Box 105)
  - RT96 3284, Undated (Box 105)
  - RT96 3285, 1995 November 12 (Box 105)
  - RT96 3286, Undated (Box 105)
  - RT96 3287, Undated (Box 105)
  - RT96 3288, Undated (Box 105)
  - RT96 3289, Undated (Box 105)
  - RT96 3290, Undated (Box 105)
  - RT96 3291, Undated (Box 105)
  - RT96 3292, Undated (Box 105)
  - RT96 3293, Undated (Box 105)
  - RT96 3294, Undated (Box 105)
  - RT96 3295, Undated (Box 105)
  - RT96 3296, Undated (Box 105)
  - RT96 3297, Undated (Box 105)
  - RT96 3298, Undated (Box 106)
  - RT96 3299, Undated (Box 106)
  - RT96 3300, Undated (Box 106)
  - RT 713, Undated (Box 106)
  - RT93 1316, Undated (Box 106)
  - Environmental Investigation Agency/Taiwan and National Asthma, Undated (Box 106)
  - Monitor News Amnesty/Apollo, Undated (Box 106)
  - Chiapas la Otra Guerra, Undated (Box 106)
- Paper Files, Circa 1990-1996; Series III
  The numbers listed refer to program numbers.
  - 101-134 (Box 107)
  - 108, General, 401-409 (Box 108)
  - 202, 410-414 [Rights and Wrongs 1994] (Box 109)
  - 201-204, United Nations (Box 110)
  - 205-209 (Box 111)
  - General, 101-105 (Box 112)
  - 210-214, 303, Tajikistan, miscellaneous, signed releases, interviews (Box 113)
  - Subject files, prospective stories, general correspondence, general administrative, interview transcripts, press (Box 114)
  - Teacher's guide, program descriptions [1993-1995], editorial and technical [1996] (Box 115)
  - Transcripts (Box 115A)
  - 300-311, General (Box 115B)
- Programs, 1993-1996; Series IV
  The series consists of Rights and Wrongs aired programs.
  The series is arranged by program number.
  - Voices of Human Rights, 1993; 101
    The program consists segments on human rights activists and the United Nations (UN) Declaration of Human Rights; Haitian refugees held by the United States Government at Guantanamo Bay; 'Video Diaries' from the Palestinian occupied territories; the Witness Program of the Lawyers Committee for Human Rights distributiion of video cameras to human rights activists around the world; the UN's Truth Commission on El Salvador; and an interview with Elliott Abrams, Reagan State Department official.
    - Master, 1 (Box 122)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 122D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 122U)
  - Africa: the Uncovered Continent, 1993 April 13; 102
    The program consists of segments on the pros and cons of humanitarian military interventions and their impact on human rights; inteviews from Somalia, Sudan, Liberia, and Rwanda; reports from Tajikistan, Iraq, and South Africa; and a profile of a human rights activist in Zaire and his NGO's work to end decades of dictatorial rule.
    - Master, 1 (Box 123)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 123D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 123U)
  - When Will War Crimes be Punished?, 1993 April 21; 103
    The program includes segments on the UN War Crimes Tribunal's plan to deal with the atrocities committed in the former Yugoslavia; interviews with Aryen Naler of Human Rights Watch and Feryal Gharahi of Equality Now, a women's group that supports rape victims in Bosnia; Susan Sarandon reading a letter from a Haitian woman being held at Guantanamo, a United States holding station for many refugees; Chris Hani, a murdered South African activist, is remembered; Poland celebrates the fiftieth anniversary of the Warsaw ghetto; and a music video of a Croatian alternative Balkan musician Nenad Bach sings about tolerance.
    - Master, 1 (Box 124)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 124D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 124U)
  - Truth As a Casualty of War, 1993 April 28; 104
    The program consists of segments on selections from Academy Award winning documentary The Panama Deception; interviews with Barbara Trent, Panama's UN Ambassador, and Jose Marin of the Center for Constitutional Rights; a debate on media restrictions on war coverage with John D. McArthur, Jr., publisher of Harper's Weekly, and Colonel Charles Ricks of the US Defense Department; a report on the Gay Pride March in Washington D.C., and on Kashmir and Chad; and a Music video featuring a Haitian band, Boukman Eksperians, which sings for human rights.
    - Master, 1 (Box 125)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 125D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 125U)
  - Ethnic Fault Lines in Europe, 1993 May 5; 105
    The program consists on segments on the rise of Hungary's fascist hate groups targeting Jews and Gypsies; an interview with philanthropist George Soros, who discusses his human rights work in Eastern Europe; reports on medical relief for Cuba, anti-war activists in Belgrade, Serbia, and human rights heroes being honored in Washington, DC; and excerpts films from the Human Rights Watch Film Festival.
    - Master, 1 (Box 126)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 126D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 126U)
  - The First Hundred Days of the Clinton Administration, 1993 May 12; 106
    The program consists of segments on Clinton's human rights policies; an interview with former US President, Jimmy Carter; and reports from Sarajevo, Sri Lanka, and Bombay, India.
    - Master, 1 (Box 127)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 127D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 127U)
  - Rape as a Weapon of War, 1993 May 19; 107
    The program consists of segments on rape as a conscious strategy of war in conflicts such as Bosnia, Kashmir, and Iraq; an interview with Charlotte Bunch from the Center of Women's Global Leadership; reports on Tibetan refugees in India, on Guatemala, and on Joan Baez's visit to Sarajevo; and a music video of Sweet Honey in the Rock singing about women's rights.
    - Master, 1 (Box 128)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 128D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 128U)
  - China and Human Rights, 1993 May 26; 108
    The program consists of "Escape from China," a secretly filmed profile of one of the Tiananmen Square uprising's young leaders and an analysis of the controversy over China's "Most Favored Nation" status as a United States trading partner.
    - Master, 1 (Box 129)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 129D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 129U)
  - Sarajevo Diaries, 1993 June 2; 109
    The program consists of segments on a video by SAGA, a Sarajevo-based group of film makers, from inside the besieged Bosnian capital; coverage of the New York Times, described as "part news, part horror movie"; a report on Prague's neo-Nazi skinheads; reports on distribution of cameras to human rights activists, on environmental protection in Haiti and Brazil, and on Kosovo; and a music video showing musicians gathering at a Sarajevo monument to bring world attention to the crisis in Bosnia.
    - Master, 1 (Box 130)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 130D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 130U)
  - 1993 Human Rights Conference Preview, 1993 June 9; 110
    The program consists of segments on the problems, priorities, and players at the 1993 United Nations World Human Rights Conference, the first to be held in 25 years; interviews with high-ranking UN officials, with US Undersecretary of State Timothy Worth, and President Jimmy Carter; UN Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali talks about the limitations of universality and the current status and future of the UN; families of murder victims tour the United States to combat the death penalty; Cambodia moves towards democracy; and a human rights advocate becomes president in Guatemala.
    - Master, 1 (Box 131)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 131D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 131U)
  - Kosovo-the Next Bosnia?, 1993 June 16; 111
    The Program consists of segments on the resistance of ethnic Albanians against Serbian occupation; Guantanamo Bay as a prison camp for Haitians; a report on El Salvador; and a discussion of United States immigration policy with Arthur Helton of the Lawyers Committee for Human rights.
    - Master, 1 (Box 132)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 132D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 132U)
  - 1993 Vienna Conference on Human Rights, 1993 June 23; 112
    The Program consists of interviews with UN officials, government delegates, NGO representatives and activists; reports on Angola, Egypt, and Liberia; and a musical salute to Nelson Mandela.
    - Master, 1 (Box 133)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 133D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 133U)
  - Female Circumcision, 1993 June 29; 113
    The program consists of efforts to treat female circumcision as a human rights abuse; Pulitzer Prize-winning author Alice Walker discusses Possessing the Secret of Joy, her novel about an African woman who responds to this cultural tradition; Diary From Hell about Manila's Smokey Mountain garbage dump, makes a link between the environment and human rights; and human rights award is given to a daily newspaper in Sarajevo.
    - Master, 1 (Box 134)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 134D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 134U)
  - Ethnic Fault Lines Revisited, 1993 July 28; 117
    The program consists of a video diary from Nogorno-Karabakh, an Armenian Christian enclave surrounded by the largely Muslim former Soviet Republic of Azeraijan; reports on Cambodia and Guatemala; report from inside Serbia, about a largely Muslim enclave that, until recently, was free from the horrors of "ethnic cleansing"; and a music video of Luis de la Guerra singing "El Costa de la Vida."
    - Master, 1 (Box 135)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 135D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 135U)
  - Indigenous People, 1993 August 25; 120
    The program consists of segments on "Papakolea: a story of Hawaiian Land" that examines homesteads, their impact on Native Hawaiian culture and heritage, and the struggle to preserve what land still remains; the discovery of gold and how the methods of its extraction threatens the lives and culture of the T'boli people of the Philippines; and Indigenous peoples from around the world perform at the Earth Summit in Rio de Janeiro.
    - Master, 1 (Box 136)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 136D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 136U)
  - North/South, 1993; 121
    The program consists of segments on the impact of the North Atlantic Free Trade Agreement and the United States Industry's search for cheaper labor and manufacturing costs on health, the environment, labor, and civil liberties; a Sarajevo "Video Diary" and a report on the Tamil Tiger guerrillas in Sri Lanka; and a report on human rights abuses against illegal immigrants at the United States/Mexico border.
    - Master, 1 (Box 137)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP Large) (Box 137D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 137U)
  - Sarajevo: Ground Zero [part I], 1993 November 3; 131
    The program consists of highlights from films produced by SAGA (Sarajevo Group of Artists) and Director Ademir Kenovic offering a chilling look of the everyday life in a city under siege.
    - Master, 1 (Box 138)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 138D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 138U)
  - Sarajevo: Ground Zero [part II], Circa 1993; 132
    The program consists of segments on SAGA's films about daily life in Sarajevo; a commentary by the Pulitzer Prize-winning New York Times correspondent John Burns; and American writer Susan Sontag stages Samuel Beckett's "Waiting for Godot" in Sarajevo and discusses its current relevance to the current situation there.
    - Master, 1 (Box 139)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 139D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 139U)
  - Whatever Happened to the War Crimes Tribunal?, 1994 April 2; 201
    The Program consists of segments on UN Security Council war crimes tribunal to examine crimes against humanity in Bosnia/Herzegovina and other former Yugoslav republics; Rights & Wrongs asks "Why?" one year later no investigations are underway; an interview with United States human rights expert, Mort Halperin; home video footage from Angola's frontlines; a commentary by Andrew Tyndall on why the television networks have ignored Mexico in their coverage of the NAFTA debate; ands an exclusive interview with Jim Sheridan, director of In the Name of the Father.
    - Master, 1 (Box 140)
    - Duplicating master, 1 videotape (Betacam-SP) (Box 140D)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 140U)